CHAPTER 007
Wha—
Wh-Why are you here?
ど どうしてお前がここに...
The one who notified me of "her" will
was Teori-san over there.
"あのかた"の意志をわたしに伝達してくれたのが
あちらにいらっしゃる手折さんなのです
N-Notify?
で... 伝達?
Don't give me that look, Araragi-kun.
そんな顔をするなって 阿良々木くん
I'll give you a full round of explanations.
ちゃんと一通り 説明してあげるからさ
You're, I mean...
お前は だって
a specialist who specializes in the extermination
of immortal apparitions, right?
不死身の怪異の退治を専門とする専門家 なんだろう?
You don't have to worry
about that for now.
今は心配しなくてもいいよ
What?
From you, your vampiric nature...
きみからは吸血鬼性が...
...has been subtracted.
引き算されている
Oh, I see.
ああ... そうか
So that's what Hachikuji meant
about what she said earlier.
さっき八九寺が言っていたのは そういう意味だったのか
It wasn't just multiplication and division,
but there's subtraction involved as well.
"掛けて割る" だけじゃあなくて "引き算" もされるという
The subtracted number
was my vampiric nature.
引く数字は 吸血鬼性だったのか
Is Yotsugi doing well? I hope she didn't
worry about the fact that she killed me.
余接は元気にしているかな?
私を殺したことを 気に病んでなければいいんだけれど
After all, she wasn't told
of the circumstances that we were in.
なにせあの子は事情を知らされていなかったからねえ
What were the circumstances?
事情って... なんだ?
To put it plainly...
端的に言うなら...
Being killed by Yotsugi in that manner
was the true role that had been given to me.
ああやって余接に殺されることこそが
私に課されていた本当の役割だったということだ
To fall to hell ahead of time, and have
all preparations to resurrect you be completed.
先に地獄に落ちておいて
きみを生き返らせる準備を整えておくことが
That was my job as a professional specialist.
プロの専門家としての 私の仕事だった
MAYOI HELL - PART TWO
CHAPTER 008
Huh?
...は?
FIVE MINUTES LATER
You mean you feigned death?
し 死んだ振りってこと?
The individual known as me had already
passed away at a point in the distant past.
私という個人は かなり昔の段階で既に死んでいたんだ
Back then, my self that Yotsugi killed
was a puppet that I controlled.
あのとき 余接が殺した私は 私の操る人形だよ
You said that Ononoki-chan
didn't know about that?
斧乃木ちゃんは... それを知らなかったって
言ってたよな?
Yup, that's right. Not just Yotsugi,
but Yoduru didn't know, either.
うん そうだ
余接だけじゃない 余弦も知らなかった
The ones who knew about this technique were
私のこの手法を知っていたのは
Gaen-senpai, and Meme Oshino.
Nobody else.
臥煙先輩と そして 忍野メメだけだ
If so, then what in the world was that farce?
だったら... いったいなんだったんだ?
あの茶番は
A farce? That was the best act in my book.
茶番か 私としては十八番なんだが
I mean, dying and resurrecting.
死んだり生き返ったりはね
You could say it's my specialty
even more than it is for vampires.
吸血鬼以上に 得意技だとも言える
Though, strictly speaking,
I'm not really resurrecting back to life.
まあ 厳密には生き返ってはいないんだけれどね
I am merely possessing a doll,
人形に憑依(ひょうい)して 媒体を経て
and through that medium,
I am regressing into the material world.
現世に回帰しているだけだから
From when?
いつから?
I became a puppeteer
人形使いになるのは
after I created the doll known as Yotsugi,
and parted ways with them.
余接という人形を作り 彼らと決別した後のことだ
Whoa.
おっと
WHITE FRAME
It seems I am being hurried.
急かされているようだな
Allow me to explain plainly.
端的に説明しよう
I quit college, and entered this field.
大学をやめて この道に入った私だが
But as Gaen-senpai was glaring at me,
I couldn't really get things to go my way.
なにせ臥煙先輩に睨(にら)まれている身だからね
なかなか思うようにはいかない
So, the hasty decision I had come up with
was to call the forbidden technique.
そこで私が短絡的に発想したのは
いわゆる禁断の手法だった
As a specialist, it's too powerful of a spell
to use, more than being a forbidden move.
専門家としては禁じ手
というより禁呪(きんじゅ)に近い
I had tried to create a doll apparition
named Tadatsuru Teori.
私は 手折正弦という人形怪異を作ろうとした
Did that succeed?
成功したのか それが
I failed, and what you see here is the result.
失敗した その結果がこの有様だ
I became something
like half-man and half-monster,
私はこの世とあの世の狭間(はざま)を漂(ただよ)う
wandering the boundaries
of the material world and the afterlife.
半人半妖のような存在となった
Well, I say it was a failure,
but I can continue to live through my dolls.
ま 失敗とは言え
人形を通じては生きていられるわけだし
And since then, I succeeded
in the mass-production of the dolls.
その後 人形の量産化には成功したから
So, if you say I'm immortal, I'm immortal.
不老不死と言えば不老不死
If you say I'm an apparition,
I'm an apparition.
怪異と言えば怪異だ
At most, I make good use of my special
constitution to strive in my own business.
精々その特異体質を活かして
商売に励むことにした
BECAUSE HE HAD SUCH A SPECIAL CONSTITUTION
HE WAS ABLE TO COME THIS FAR OUTSIDE
OF GAEN-SAN'S NETWORK...
Then, why did you pretend to die?
じゃあ どうして 死んだ振りなんか
It was last month.
先月のことだった
One request came flying for me
as a specialist.
専門家としての私に ひとつ依頼が舞い込んだ
It was a request to resolve the anomalies
that were happening in your town.
きみの住んでいる町で起こっている異変を解決して欲しいという依頼だった
The contents of that request
had targeted you and ex-Kiss-shot.
その依頼の内容は
きみや旧キスショットを的にしたものだった
You guys were certified as harmless
within Gaen-senpai's network,
臥煙先輩のネットワーク内では無害認定されているきみ達ではあったが
but an apparition guarded by the network
was something I targeted as my top priority.
むしろネットワークで保護されている怪異など
私にとっては最優先で狙うべき
Request or not, you were a target
that I should be on the move for.
依頼がなくとも動くべき対象だった
This guy took my two little sisters
and one underclassman as hostages.
こいつは 二人の妹と後輩を一人
人質に取るなんていう
He pulled off such a vicious, cruel act.
悪辣非道(あくらつひどう)な真似をしてのけたのだ
BLACK FRAME
If something had
not been done in advance,
もしも事前に手が打たれていなければ
I wonder if I would have been
unscathed by it all.
果たして無事で済んでいたかどうか...
Don't say scary things like that.
怖いことを言うなよ
I'm the one who is scared saying this.
これを言っていて怖いのは私だよ
To think that Suruga Kanbaru
was the daughter of the Gaen clan...
まさか神原駿河が 臥煙家の娘だったとは
When I think about what would've happened
if I had injured her without
何も知らずに危害を加えていたらと思うと
knowing anything, I start trembling.
身震いを禁じ得ない
I'm glad that I had heard things in advance.
先に聞いておいて本当によかった
Tadatsuru, so you had heard something
from Gaen-san before you received the request?
正弦 お前は依頼が来る前に
臥煙さんから何かを聞いていたってことなのか?
No, it was someone else that was
the middleman between me and Gaen-senpai.
いや 私と臥煙先輩との間を仲立ちしたのは 別人だよ
MIDDLEMAN
To the word "middleman,"
I had one inspiration.
仲立ち という言葉に ひとつの直感を得た
Oshino?
忍野?
OSHINO
Meme Oshino?
忍野メメ?
CHAPTER 009
Correct.
ご名答
Yes, that man
who acts as he sees through things.
そう あの見透かしたような男が だ
Despite being one of the leading members
of Gaen-senpai's network,
臥煙先輩のネットワークの幹部クラスでありながら
he reached out and contacted me.
私に接触を取ってくるとは
That made me feel like
he was still a free man as ever.
相変わらず自由自在な男だと思ったよ
He had said that because I was outside
of Gaen-senpai's network,
臥煙先輩のネットワークの外にいる私だからこそ
there was something I could do.
できることがあると言っていたね
あいつは
And that was when you had heard
of Kanbaru's background in advance?
その際にお前は
神原の出自やらをあらかじめ聞いていたってことか?
Yup. And there was talk about you as well,
or should I say, talk about you guys?
うん それに きみの話も出た
きみ達の話 と言うべきかな
Now that I think about it, he was appealing to me
about how safe you guys were.
今から思うと
あいつはきみ達の安全性をアピールしていたんだな
By the way, I realized that he had
ちなみに私の正体が人形だと
seen my true identity as just a doll,
was at that time as well.
あいつが見透かしていたことを知ったのはそのときだった
No, now that I think about it,
maybe he was threatening me?
いや 今から思うと脅されたのかもしれないな?
Like, "if you laid a hand on my friends,
I'll disclose your true nature."
僕の友達に手を出したら きみの正体をバラすぞ と
TO THINK HE HAD TAKEN COUNTERMEASURES
TO PREPARE FOR A SITUATION THAT IS EXPECTED TO HAPPEN
This was the argument he had made.
あいつの言い分はこうだった
"Koyomi Araragi and Shinobu Oshino."
"阿良々木暦と忍野忍 彼らは今 基本的には無害だ"
"Currently, they are basically harmless."
"As long as you leave them untouched,
there are no problems."
"手を出さなければ 何も問題はない"
"However, I'm not saying cases
that deviate from the norm don't exist."
"ただし 基本から逸脱するケースがないわけでもない
"The case IS where Araragi-kun colludes with
Shinobu-chan, and continues to vampirify himself."
それは阿良々木くんが忍ちゃんと結託し
吸血鬼化を繰り返した場合だ"
In other words, that man was deeply concerned
about the arrival of a situation
つまり 阿良々木くんがそうせざるを得ないような状況の来訪を
あの男は危惧していた
where you had to do as such, Araragi-kun.
He seemed to know you'd willingly be reckless
when it came to situations of that sort.
そういった状況に際して
きみが無茶をすることを厭わないことはわかっていたようだ
Even if he knew...
わかられてもな...
If such turn of events were to happen,
I may receive some sort of a request.
そういう展開になった際に
私になんらかの依頼が来るかもしれない
吸血鬼退治の依頼が だ
A request to hunt down vampires, that is.
そうなったら積年の恨みを忘れ
臥煙先輩と接点を持ってくれ
He wanted me to "forget my grudges from the past,
and seek contact with Gaen-senpai."
"And at that point, Gaen-senpai
should be waiting to hear from you."
そのとき 臥煙先輩はきみからの連絡を待っているはずだ
"Because Gaen-senpai can't move,
as she has her position to hold."
立場のある臥煙先輩からは動けないから
Back then, I didn't really understand
what he was talking about.
そのときは 何を言っているのかよくわからなかったけれど
But in reality, things went exactly
like he thought it would go.
実際にその通りの展開になったというわけだ
And that's why, when that request came flying in,
indeed, to exterminate you guys,
だから 私のところに まさしく
きみ達を退治すべきだという依頼が舞い込んできたとき
it sent shivers up my spine.
ぞっとしたものだよ
At the same time,
I found it rather strange.
と 同時に不思議でもあった
If he was so concerned
about this turn of events,
この展開を危惧していたのであれば
why didn't Oshino want to do something
about it on his own?
どうして忍野は自分でなんとかしようと思わないのだろう
That was something I became intrigued in.
その辺りが興味になった
That's why I thought I'd play along
with his little arrangement.
だからここはあいつのはからいに乗ってやることにした
I contacted Gaen-senpai.
私は臥煙先輩に連絡を取った
AND SO, THE CURTAIN ROSE ON THE FARCE PLAY.
CHAPTER 010
Araragi-san, that's your ride
to go back to the material world.
阿良々木さん あれが現世からのお迎えですよ
You really are running out of time.
本当に時間がなくなってきてますよ
If you miss that thread, Araragi-san, you really
will continue to burn forever here in Avici.
あの糸を逃したら
阿良々木さんは本当に阿鼻地獄で永遠に焼かれ続けることになります
And so, Teori-san, I'm terribly sorry,
but can you cut that story out about here?
というわけで手折さん 申し訳ないんですけれども
もうその話 ここでやめてもらってもいいですか?
No, wait, Hachikuji.
いや待て八九寺
It wasn't okay to just
merely turn down the request?
依頼を普通に断るっていうんじゃ駄目だったのか?
"It's better for me to play along
with what the enemy intended."
ここは "敵" の思惑に乗っておくのがいい
That was the conclusion
Gaen-senpai and I came to.
というのが私と臥煙先輩の出した結論だった
I did say it was better to play along
with what they intended,
思惑に乗っておくのがいいと言ったものの
but their intent is not something
I clearly understand.
その思惑が何なのか
はっきりわかっているわけではない
I'm doing this because
I want to find out what it is.
それを探りたくてやっていることだ
That, and simultaneously,
そしてまた 同時に
きみの吸血鬼化の進行を止めるために必要な処置でもあった
it was a measure necessary in order to stop
progression of you turning into a vampire.
So that I can come to this side
like this, and guide you...
私がこうして こちら側に来て
きみを誘導するという
Since it was right after
I played a despicable character,
嫌われ者を演じた直後のことだったので
I also had to have some assistance
from Hachikuji-chan right there to pull it off.
その辺は そこの八九寺ちゃんにも協力してもらうことになったがね
I was allowed to assist for this.
協力させていただきました
KOYOMI ARARAGI
TADATSURU TEORI
It's in the parenthesis, cameo appearance.
（友情出演）です
It shows up
at the end of the ending credits.
エンドロールの最後のほうに出る奴です
MAYOI HACHIKUJI
(CAMEO APPEARANCE)
So kill once to reset, and resurrect just
the "human" part of my physical body, huh?
いったん殺してリセットして
僕の肉体の "人間" の部分だけを生き返らせる か
IF SO, THEN, IT WOULD'VE BEEN NICE
IF THEY TOLD ME IN ADVANCE,
BUT IF THEY DIDN'T TELL ME, THAT MEANS
THERE WERE CIRCUMSTANCES
PREVENTING THEM FROM TELLING ME IN ADVANCE
THAT PART MAY BE THE TACTIC
THEY ARE TAKING AGAINST THE ENEMY
THERE'S NO WAY FOR ME TO KNOW FROM MY VIEWPOINT.
Of course, if we were to use the demon sword
"Yume Watari" to revive you
もっとも 妖刀 "心渡" で殺したきみを
妖刀 "夢渡" で生き返らせたら
after killing you with
the demon sword "Kokoro Watari,"
it may revive you
just the way you were, as a vampire.
吸血鬼としてのきみがそのまま生き返りかねなくて
That would have put us back
at square one.
それでは元の木阿弥(もくあみ)だからね
In order to not do that, we needed me
そうしないために地獄側から
to interfere as a specialist
over from the hell side of things.
私という専門家の横入りが必要になったというわけだ
Without making that correction, there was
nothing we could do against the enemy.
その点を修正しないことには
敵に対して手の打ちようがないというのも
That was the mutual conclusion
that both Gaen-senpai and I came to.
私と臥煙先輩の共通した結論だ
Let us be on our way, Araragi-san.
行きましょうよ 阿良々木さん
This thing is alive.
生きてんじゃねえかよ
Come to think, I hadn't asked yet.
そう言えば まだ聞いてなかったな
Yes?
はい?
I was supposedly slain at
North Shirahebi Shrine in the real world.
どうして現世で 北白蛇神社で斬られたはずの僕が
地獄ではあの公園で目覚めたんだ?
Why did I wake up
in that park over in hell?
That bothers you that much?
それ そんなに気になりますか?
It's not enough to bother me per se, but...
気になるというほどでもないが
NO.
I KNOW. I'M JUST DELAYING.
TO CLIMB THIS WHITE SNAKE—
TO RESURRECT BACK INTO LIFE.
I'M DELAYING IT FURTHER AND FURTHER
PARK
About the shift, well, I don't care.
ズレ云々は まあどうでもいいや
But, if you know what the name
of that park is, I'd like to know.
だけど あの公園の名前を 知ってるって言うんなら
教えて欲しいもんだ
NAMISHIRO
Is it "Namishiro," or "Rouhaku"?
"なみしろ" なんだか "ろうはく" なんだか
"Shirohebi" Park.
しろへび公園
The correct way to read the name
is "Shirohebi" Park, if you go back to its origin.
しろへび公園と読むのが正しい 元を糺せば
Eh? Shirohebi?
え? しろへび?
HEBI
(SNAKE)
It's not the "insect" radical,
but the "water" radical.
虫偏ではなくさんずい偏だよ
HEBI
Shirohebi.
沱白
SHIROHEBI
Somewhere along the way,
someone miswrote and HEBI turned into NAMI.
どこかで書き間違えられて
"沱" が "浪" になったのが 難読になった理由だよ
It's why the location became hard to read.
HEBI
NAMI
Wait, "shirohebi"...
白蛇って...
...North "Shirahebi" Shrine.
北... 白蛇神社
NORTH SHIRAHEBI SHRINE
Yup. That's what it means.
うん そういうことだ
元々北白蛇神社は あそこにあったんだよ
Originally, North Shirahebi Shrine
used to be at that location.
That's why that slight shift occurred.
だからズレた
You've heard the story that this shrine
was one that had been relocated, perhaps?
この神社が移築されたものであるという話は
聞いたことが... あるかな?
Yeah, that's—
ああ それは...
I think it was a mistake in connection,
確か接続ミスであり
歪みの原因にもなったとか なんとか...
and became a reason for distortion,
or something.
Right, as it was something like bringing
the god of the seas on top of a mountain.
そうだね 海の神を山に持ってきたようなものなんだから
Though, to be precise, it wasn't a sea but a lake.
厳密には海ではなく 湖 だが
Lake? I think I've heard about that
from someone at some point...
湖? それも どこかで誰かに聞いたような...
Well, you should
get on your way soon, Araragi-kun.
じゃあ そろそろ出発しようか阿良々木くん
Please give my regards
to Gaen-senpai. And to Yotsugi.
臥煙先輩によろしく そして余接によろしく
Please cherish Yotsugi on my behalf as well.
私の分まで余接を可愛がってやってくれ
Yeah, got it.
ああ わかった
But is it all right
for someone like me to resurrect?
でも 僕なんかが生き返っていいのかな
CHAPTER 011
Hachikuji!
八九寺!
"Is it all right
for someone like me to resurrect?"
僕なんかが生き返っていいのかなとは
なんという言い草ですか
What kind of a statement is that?
What, Araragi-san.
Are you chickening out?
なんですか 阿良々木さん
怖気づきましたか
You don't want
to go through difficult ordeals?
大変な思いとかしたくないですか
Are you tired of it all?
疲れちゃいましたか
No.
いや
There really was a feeling
like a tense thread snapping.
張りつめていた糸が切れたような気持ちは
確かにあって
I didn't really have the feeling of
"I was finally able to die," either.
"やっと死ねた" って気持ちも
ないじゃあないんだ
You can only say that because
you don't know the hardships of hell.
地獄の苦しさを知らないからそんなことを言えるんですよ?
You really are quite fortunate
merely because you can be resurrected.
生き返れるというだけで
本当 相当な幸運だというのに
FORTUNATE
But I feel like there are tons of other people
who deserve to be resurrected more than me.
なんていうか... 僕じゃなくて
他に生き返るべき奴はもっといると思うのに
Is it all right for me to be resurrected?
僕が生き返っていいのかって気持ちかな
It's not that I don't want to be resurrected,
but I feel I'm cutting in line when I shouldn't be.
生き返りたくないってわけじゃあないんだけれど
やっちゃいけない順番抜かしをしている気分になる
You do, indeed!
ありますよ
You have the right to be resurrected.
生き返る資格は あります
Araragi-san, you have at least
that much of a qualification.
それくらいの資格は阿良々木さんにはあります
Because you've done
at least that much to begin with!
だってそれくらいのことはしてきたじゃないですか!
Yes, you have. I know all too well!
ええ してきましたとも
わたしがようく知っています!
If you're not being resurrected,
who are you saying should be resurrected?
あなたが生き返らなきゃ誰が生き返るって言うんですか
Without a doubt,
you are the first person in line!
文句なく あなたが一番手ですよ!
If you say weak-minded things so much,
I might end up hating you.
あんまり弱気なことばかり言っていると
嫌いになってしまいますよ
Listen up, Araragi-san.
いいですか 阿良々木さん
The Araragi-san that I know...
わたしの知る阿良々木さんは...
loves girls, loves young girls, loves little girls,
loves the skirt linings, loves women's hips,
少女が好きで 幼女が好きで 童女が好きで スカートの裏地が好きで 女子の腰つきが好きで
loves big boobs, loves to be handled roughly,
loves his older little sister,
大きなおっぱいが好きで 雑に扱われるのが好きで 大きな妹が好きで
loves his younger little sister, loves mature women,
loves toplessness, loves bloomers,
小さな妹が好きで 熟女が好きで 上半身裸が好きで ブルマが好きで
loves school-issued swimsuits,
loves class reps,
スクール水着が好きで 委員長が好きで
loves girls who use "boku,"
loves cat ears, loves girls playing sports...
僕っ子が好きで 猫耳が好きで スポーツ少女が好きで
Hold on a second.
ちょっと待って
Hold it, hold it, hold it, hold it!
待って待って待って待って
My heart is about to completely snap right now.
心がそろそろぽっきり折れそうなんだけれど
And you were someone who loves to be alive.
生きるのが大好きな人だったじゃないですか
IT WAS SO OBVIOUS THAT I HAD FORGOTTEN.
I CAME TO THE BRINK OF DEATH MANY, MANY TIMES—
AND EACH TIME, I NARROWLY ESCAPED DEATH
BECAUSE OF THAT, I HAD COMPLETELY FORGOTTEN.
You're right.
そうだよな...
If I'm not alive, I can't cherish girls at all.
生きていなければ
少女を愛(め)でることもできないものな
Uhm, no, that's not exactly
what I wanted to tell you.
あ いえ
わたしが言いたかったのはそういうことではないんですけれども
To say there was a shift
in the meaning of life...
生きる意味がブレるなんてよく言ったもんだ...
There was plenty of meaning
merely by staying alive.
生きてるだけで
十分に意味はあったじゃないか
If you love being alive,
that's all you really needed.
生きてることが好きなら それだけでよかった
Because I was able to love
all sorts of things, and people.
色んな物を 色んな人を好きになれたんだから
When you say that in this context,
it may be a bit misleading.
この文脈で言うといささか語弊(ごへい)がありそうですけれどね
If I give the signal from this end, Gaen-senpai
will pull you up from her end. That's about it.
私がこちらから合図を送れば
あちらから臥煙先輩が引っ張り上げてくれるイメージだ
Got it.
わかった
I'm much obliged, Tadatsuru.
世話になったな 正弦
Tadatsuru-san.
...正弦さん
No need to be formal
after all we've been through.
今更 畏(かしこ)まることはないよ
As long as you continue to attempt protecting
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade,
きみがキスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードを
保護しようとし続ける限り
...you will be my enemy.
きみは私の敵だよ
Even then, I'm much obliged
for this particular case.
それでも 今回のことでは世話になった
I never thought I'd be able
to chat with you like this.
お前とこんな風に話せるだなんて思ってなかったから
Someday, when we have time,
I'd like to settle down and talk with you again.
いつか時間があるときに
もうちょっと腰を落ち着けて話したい
If you don't mind doing so
while we kill each other.
殺し合いながらでもよければ
Hachikuji.
What are you going to do from here?
八九寺 お前は これからどうするんだ?
What?
はい?
Me? After I see you off, Araragi-san,
わたしですか? わたしは 阿良々木さんを見送ったら
賽の河原に戻って石積みの毎日ですよ
I'm going back to the banks of hell
to pile stones up every day.
Perhaps I may reincarnate as the child
of you and Senjougahara-san.
ひょっとすると阿良々木さんと戦場ヶ原さんの子供として
転生することになるかもしれませんね
That's pretty heavy.
それは重いな
Now then.
では
I'm good. Send me off at any time.
いいぜ いつでも送ってくれ
Then, let's countdown.
じゃあ カウントダウン で行くよ
10... 9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4... 3...
2...
1...
Ignition.
点火(イグニション)
That's right. Hachikuji said the first person
who should be resurrected is me.
そうだ 八九寺は生き返るべき一番手は僕だと言ってくれたけれど
But, at the least, I am being
resurrected by shoving Hachikuji aside.
少なくとも 八九寺をさしおいて
僕は生き返ってしまうのだ
To part with Mayoi Hachikuji...
八九寺真宵と別れるのは...
How many times does this make?
これで何度目になるのだろう
H-Hachikuji!
は 八九寺い!
Oh, Araragi-kun, one more thing!
ああ 阿良々木くん ひとつだけ!
I'll tell you the name of the "enemy"
who requested me to exterminate you!
私に 退治を依頼した
"敵" の名前を 私から教えておこう!
Ougi.
扇
Ougi Oshino.
忍野扇
CHAPTER 012
This is the epilogue,
or the punch line for this episode.
後日談というか 今回のオチ
Really...
まったく...
To bring Hachikuji-chan with you, Koyomin.
八九寺ちゃんを連れてくるだなんて こよみん
You always are someone who goes
way beyond any of my expectations.
きみって奴はいつだって私の期待を遥かに超えてくれるものだ
But for now, Koyomin,
とりあえずこよみん
can you please ask this scary,
beautiful lady to pull back her claws?
この怖い美女に
爪を引っ込めてくれるようお願いしてくれないかな?
Hey, you.
よう お前様
Hmph. Well, I guess both needless killings
and futile gashes have been avoided.
まあ 無駄な殺生(せっしょう)も
無益な切傷もせずには済んだか のう
Though, it was the first time for me
to see "Yume Watari" activate.
"夢渡" の発動を見るのは初めてじゃったが...
You fool, you made me worry.
阿呆(あほう)が 心配させおって
And, you abducted a young girl from hell.
You really are reckless.
しかも 少女をひとり地獄からかどわかしてくるとは
無茶苦茶じゃのう
Hey, Shinobu. This is really bad
no matter how you think about it, right?
なあ忍 これって
どう考えてもまずいよな...
Did once again, Hachikuji fulfill the conditions
for the "darkness" to be triggered?
これでまた 八九寺は "くらやみ" の
発動条件を満たしてしまったんじゃ...
And I'm saying that's why
you made a fine play, Koyomin.
そこがこよみんのファインプレーだと言っている
Thanks to Koyomin's miracle here,
こよみんのミラクルのお蔭で
ここから先の勝負をいくらか優位に進められそうだよ
it looks like we'll be able to take
a slight advantage in the battles to come.
The lost girl.
She's a pawn that I had been wanting.
迷子の少女 欲しかった駒(こま)だよ
But with how things are turning out,
しかしこうなった以上
私はもう少しだけ協力を要請しなければならないだろうね
it looks like I must request help
for a little while longer.
For now, Koyomin, I want you
to head over to your entrance exams.
とりあえずは こよみんには受験に向かってもらおうか
If you head over now, you'll still make it.
今からなら余裕で間に合うだろう
Do your best.
頑張ってね
Well, I will do my best.
ま まあ 頑張りますけれど
Koyomin, I'll have you working for me
starting tomorrow.
こよみんには明日から動いてもらうことにする
Everything will be over
before the graduation ceremony.
なあに 卒業式までにはすべて 終わっているよ
I have all of my weapons now.
武器は揃(そろ)った
Let's settle the score, Koyomin.
決着をつけようじゃないか こよみん
Strangely enough, tomorrow is White Day, right?
奇(く)しくも明日はホワイトデーじゃあないか
It's the perfect timing to end the story of this town,
where a white snake once reigned.
かつて白蛇が君臨したこの町の物語を終えるには
ちょうどいい頃合いだろう
We're starting our counterattack!
反撃開始だよん